Register of the Eric Voegelin papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Eric Voegelin papers
1901-1997
75070
Hoover Institution Archives
133 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 7 card file boxes, 5 envelopes (60.2 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches and writings, reports, memoranda, conference proceedings, and printed matter relating to the philosophy of history, the philosophy of science, various other aspects of philosophy, and to political science and other social sciences, especially as considered from a philosophical perspective. Also available on microfilm.
Voegelin, Eric, 1901-1985.
Access
The collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1975, with increments to the collection acquired between 1975 and 2012.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Form Available
The collection is also available on microfilm.
Related Collections
Barry Cooper, Jodi Bruhn and John von Heyking interviews, Hoover Institution Archives
International Conference on the Work of Eric Voegelin conference papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical Note
1901 January 3 Born, Cologne, Germany
1910 Family relocated to Vienna, Austria
1922 Dr. rerum politicarum, University of Vienna
1924-1927 Fellow, Rockefeller Foundation
1928 Author, Uber die Form des amerikanischen Geistes
1928 Habilitation, University of Vienna
1929-1936 Privatdozent, University of Vienna
1932 Married Lissy Onken (1906-)
1933 Author, Rasse und Staat and Die Rassenidee in der Geistesgeschichte von Ray bis Carus
1936 Author, Der autoritäre Staat
1936-1938 Adjunct professor ("Extraordinarius") of political science, University of Vienna
1938 Author, Die politischen Religionen Immigrated to the United States
1938-1939 Tutor and instructor, Harvard University
1939 Instructor, Bennington College, Vermont
1939-1942 Professor, University of Alabama, Tuscaloosa
1942-1959 Professor, Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge
1944 Naturalized
1952 Author, The New Science of Politics
1956 Author, Order and History, Vol.I: Israel and Revelation
1957 Author, Order and History, Vol.II: The World of the Polis and Vol.III: Plato and Aristotle
1958-1969 Professor, University of Munich, West Germany Founded the Institut für Politische Wissenschaft [renamed Geschwister-Scholl-Institut für Politische Wissenschaft (Universität München) in 1968]
1959 Author, Wissenschaft, Politik und Gnosis
1966 Author, Anamnesis. Zur Theorie der Geschichte und Politik
1969-1974 Henry Salvatori Distinguished Scholar, Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace
1974 Author, Order and History, Vol.IV: The Ecumenic Age
1974-1985 Senior Research Fellow, Hoover Institution
1975 Author, From Enlightenment to Revolution
1985 January 19 Died, Stanford, California
1987 Author, Order and History, Vol.V: In Search of Order (published posthumously)
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers document the career and life of Eric Voegelin, a German-American philosopher and political scientist. The collection includes correspondence, speeches and writings, reports, memoranda, conference proceedings, photographs, and printed matter related to the philosophy of history and the philosophy of science. The material is arranged in two similar groups, with incremental materials dating from 1901 to 1996.
Eric Voegelin was born in Germany in 1901. He moved with his family to Austria in 1910, going through the habilitation and privatdozent processes at the University of Vienna, where he became a professor. When Nazi forces annexed Austria in 1938, Voegelin fled to Switzerland, and then immigrated to the United States, where he was naturalized in 1944. The Biographical File provides documentation on Voegelin's life, including materials related to his move to the United States, anniversary tributes and memorials, and honorary degrees.
Voegelin was a prolific author, publishing works in German and English. Speeches and Writings include drafts, correspondence, and notes for such works as the multi-volume Order and History and History of Political Ideas, which was published after Voegelin's death.
Voegelin taught at several universities in the United States and abroad, including the University of Vienna, Harvard University, Bennington College, the University of Alabama, Louisiana State University, and the University of Munich. Course Material contains Voegelin's lecture materials, syllabi, and reading lists for courses that he taught.
While in Munich, Voegelin founded the Institut für Politische Wissenschaft, which was later renamed the Geschwister-Scholl-Institut für Politische Wissenschaft (Universität München). The Office File includes documents related to this institution, such as correspondence, reports, and minutes.
In 1932, Voegelin married Lissy Onken, also known as Luise Betty Voegelin. The Lissy Voegelin File contains correspondence (some of which concerns Voegelin and his writing) and appointment books.
The Photographs and Postcards in the collection have a focus on artifacts, with images from sites and cultures around that world. One folder of artifact photographs bears the name of Marie König, who has been cited as an influence on Voegelin in the area of Stone Age symbolism (Cooper). Negatives in the collection contain scenic views of Yellowstone National Park, Niagara Falls, Stanford University, Vienna, and various cities in the United States.
The majority of the incremental materials in the collection are described in an inventory of the estate of Lissy Voegelin. Inventory numbers within the container list refer to the original numbers given to materials in this inventory, which can be found with the Eric Voegelin finding aid in the Hoover Archives reading room.
Source: Cooper, Barry. "Voegelin and his Contemporaries." Voegelin View. Accessed through: http://voegelinview.com/all-Current-Articles/voegelin-and-his-contemporaries-pt-1.html
International relations.; Philosophy.; Political science.; Science--Philosophy.; Social sciences--Philosophy.; History--Philosophy.; Philosophers.
- Biographical File, 1935-1983
  Scope and Contents note
  Address lists, autobiographical notes, bibliographies, correspondence, genealogical records, honorary degrees, reports, resolutions, schedules, and tributes, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Address and distribution lists (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Anniversary tributes
    - Politische Ordnung und menschliche Existenz:Festgabe für Eric Voegelin zum 60 Geburtstag, Herausgegeben von Alois Dempf, Hannah Arendt und Friedrich Engel-Janosi (Box-folder 1: 2)
      Announcements, bibliography, and reviews.
    - The Philosophy of Order: Essays on History, Consciousness and Politics, For Eric Voegelin on His Eightieth Birthday, Edited by Peter J. Opitz and Gregor Sebba, 1981 January 3
      - Bibliography; contents table; reviews by Dante Germino, Thomas Langan, and Johannes Hampel; address list for the Tabula Gratulatoria; and correspondence with Peter J. Opitz and Gregor Sebba (Box-folder 1: 3)
      - Contributions
        - Aron, Raymond (Box-folder 1: 4)
        - Boers, Hendrikus (Box-folder 1: 5)
        - Bueno, Anibal A. (Box-folder 1: 6)
        - Hollweck, Thomas (Box-folder 1: 7)
        - Lifton, Robert J. (Box-folder 1: 8)
        - Manchester, Peter (Box-folder 1: 9)
        - Talmon, J. L. (Box-folder 1: 10)
        - Opitz, Peter J. (Box-folder 1: 11)
        - Sebba, Gregor (Box-folder 1: 12)
        - Wagner, Helmut R. (Box-folder 1: 13)
      - Documentary appendix with introduction by Gregor Sebba, correspondence with Alfred Schütz,"In Memoriam Alfred Schütz" by Eric Voegelin, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - Articles and clippings (Box-folder 1: 15)
    See also SUBJECT FILE, Geschwister-Scholl-Institut für Politische Wissenschaft (Universität München)
  - Autobiographical notes, taped and edited by Ellis Sandoz (Box-folder 1: 16)
    See also Incremental speeches and writings, Autobiographical Reflections
  - Awards
    - Benjamin Evans Lippincott Award, 1978 August 31 (Box-folder 2: 1)
      Contains correspondence with B. E. Lippincott, Evron M. Kirkpatrick, W. Glenn Campbell, and Richard W. Lyman. Also includes a description by B. E. Lippincott of the purpose and scope of the award.
    - Gold medal "München leuchtet - Den Freund Münchens," Munich, West Germany, 1981 May 20 (Box-folder 2: 2)
      Includes clippings and correspondence with Erich Kiesel and Wolfgang Czisch.
  - Bibliographical lists (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Bibliographies and curricula vitae, 1940 February (Box-folder 2: 4)
    Includes information provided by Eric Voegelin before the Excelsior Literary Society, Alabama, and in a draft of a letter sent to an unidentified university when applying for a position. See also Subject File, Vienna, Volkshochschule Wien Volksheim; and Subject File, United States, Citizenship.
  - Book orders. (Box-folder 2: 5)
    See also CORRESPONDENCE, Stephen M. DuBrul, Jr.
  - Genealogical records and correspondence regarding the name of Voegelin (Box-folder 2: 6)
    See also Honorary degrees, Universität Augsburg.
  - Honorary degrees
    - University of Notre Dame, Indiana, 1974 May 19 (Box-folder 2: 7)
      Contains correspondence with Theodore M. Hesburgh, Gerhart Niemeyer, James V. Gibbons, James T. Burtchaell.
    - Marquette University, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 1975 May 18 (Box-folder 2: 8)
      Contains correspondence with John P. Raynor and a press release.
    - Colorado College, Colorado Springs, 1980 June 2 (Box-folder 2: 9)
      Contains correspondence with Timothy Fuller and Lloyd E. Worner, and an introduction of Eric Voegelin by Timothy Fuller.
    - Universität Augsburg, West Germany, 1981 May 13 (Box-folder 2: 10)
      Notes and outline of address entitled "Common Sense und magische Politik;" clippings; and correspondence with Arno Baruzzi, Johannes Hampel, Theo Stammen.
    - Dominican School of Philosophy and Theology, Berkeley, California, 1982 June 11 (Box-folder 3: 1)
      Notes, outline of commencement address, and correspondence with Kevin Wall and Antoninus A. Wall. Includes a paper by Michael Morrissey.
    - Emory University, Atlanta, Georgia, 1983 May 16 (Box-folder 3: 2)
      Correspondence with Tom Bertrand, Theodore Weber, and James T. Laney.
  - Lecture lists (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - Membership certificates (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Notices (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Schedules and appointment calendars (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - Subject file
    Announcements, correspondence, eulogies, programs, and legal documents.
    - Library assessment by Florian Shasky (Box-folder 3: 8)
    - Memorial service, Stanford Memorial Church, 1985 February 4 (Box-folder 3: 9)
    - Trips and/or lecture tours
      See also Speaking Engagements and Trips File.
      - 1969, Europe (Box-folder 3: 10)
      - 1970, Europe and Canada (Box-folder 3: 11)
      - 1971, Europe (Box-folder 3: 12)
      - 1972, Europe (Box-folder 3: 13)
      - 1973, Iran, Turkey, Vienna (Box-folder 3: 14)
    - United States
      - Citizenship, 1958-1964 (Box-folder 3: 15)
        Includes correspondence with William Y. Elliott, Theodore M. Hesburgh, Edward J. Hickey (United States. Department of State. Passport Division), and Congressman Francis E. Walter regarding the passage of H.R. 5902, "A Bill for the Relief of Eric Voegelin."
      - Departure for, 1938 (Box-folder 3: 16)
      - Residence status, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 3: 17)
    - Vienna
      - General, 1935-1938 (Box-folder 3: 18)
      - Libel suit against H. Pfeifer who portrayed Eric Voegelin as a Jew (Box-folder 3: 19)
      - Volkshochschule Wien Volksheim, 1936-1938 (Box-folder 3: 20)
    - Zurich, 1938 (Box-folder 3: 21)
  - Subscription lists (Box-folder 3: 22)
  - Work progress reports (Box-folder 3: 23)
- Correspondence (Alphabetical File), 1928-1984
  Incoming and outgoing correspondence arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
  - General
    - Unidentified (Box-folder 4: 1)
    - 1930-1971 (Box-folder 4: 2-28)
    - 1972-1984 (Box-folder 5: 1-13)
  - Academia Moralis (2), 1953 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Adamovich, Ludwig (3), 1950 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Adamson, Kenneth M. (5), 1972-1974 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Adler, Mortimer J. (4), 1939 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Agnew, Spiro (2), 1970 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - Albrecht, Dieter (2), 1969 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - Albrizio, Conrad (21), 1945-1960 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - Algozin, Keith (6), 1971-1974 (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - All Souls College (Denis Mack Smith) (5), 1973 (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - Allen, Richard V. (83), 1960-1980 (Box-folder 6: 10)
    Includes correspondence with William C. Havard, F. A. Hermens, Evron M. Kirkpatrick, E. M. Fels, Hans Raupach
  - Allers, Rudolf (2), 1949 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - Altizer, Thomas J. J. (3), 1983-1985 (Box-folder 6: 12)
  - America: National Catholic Weekly Review (Robert C. Hartnett) (3), 1954 (Box-folder 6: 13)
  - American Defense--Harvard Group (Taylor Starck) (2), 1943 (Box-folder 6: 14)
    Includes letter of Eric Voegelin regarding Alfred von Verdross-Drossberg, Adolf Merkl, Otto Brunner, Ottmar Diettrich, and Georg Jungwirth.
  - American Political Science Association (9), 1938-1984 (Box-folder 6: 15)
  - American Political Science Review (6), 1943-1975 (Box-folder 6: 16)
  - American Society for Political and Legal Philosophy (7), 1956-1973 (Box-folder 6: 17)
  - American Sociological Review (2), 1936 (Box-folder 6: 18)
    Includes notes of Eric Voegelin, and a handwritten article he may have submitted to the journal
  - Amerika-Institut der Universität München (William C. Lehmann) (39), 1951-1952 (Box-folder 6: 19)
    Includes correspondence with Heinrich Brüning, Alois Dempf, Bayerisches Staatsministerium für Unterricht und Kultus (Hans Rheinfelder), Rockefeller Foundation (Eduard d'Arms, Chadbourne Gilpatrick), United States. Department of State. German Cultural Affairs (Vaughn De Long)
  - Anderson, Bernhard W. (12), 1959-1962 (Box-folder 6: 20)
  - Anderson, Quentin (8), 1971 (Box-folder 6: 21)
  - Arbeitsgemeinschaft Selbstständiger Unternehmer (3), 1969 (Box-folder 6: 22)
  - Arendt, Hannah (13), 1951-1972 (Box-folder 6: 23)
  - Armanen Verlag (Ernst Krieck) (4), 1933-1934 (Box-folder 6: 24)
  - Aron, Raymond (16), 1959-1971 (Box-folder 6: 25)
  - Aufricht, Hans (29), 1938-1964 (Box-folder 7: 1)
    Includes correspondence with James Hart, Marcus M. Wilkerson, Herbert W. Briggs
  - Austrian Action (28), 1941 (Box-folder 7: 2)
    Includes correspondence with Ferdinand Czernin, Gregor Sebba, Willibald Plöchl, Friedrich Engel-Janosi, Austrian National Council, Free Austrian Movement. See also Richard Coudenhove-Kalergi and BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, Residence status
  - Austrian Institute (Dietrich von Hildebrand) (3), 1943-1944 (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - Ayers, Robert C. (2), 1967 (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - Babin, James L. (3), 1971-1972 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - Baerwald, Hans H. (15), 1958-1959 (Box-folder 7: 6)
    Includes correspondence with the United States Educational Commission in the Federal Republic of Germany (Fulbright Commission)
  - Baird, Andrew (Fortune), (6), 1979 (Box-folder 7: 7)
    Includes his article on Eric Voegelin based on his interview of the latter
  - Balthasar, Hans Urs von (2), 1950 (Box-folder 7: 8)
  - Bark, William C. (1), 1967 (Box-folder 7: 9)
  - Baroody, William J. (2), 1969 (Box-folder 7: 10)
  - Barraclough, Geoffrey (28), 1961-1975 (Box-folder 7: 11)
  - Barsch, Claus-Ekkehard (13), 1971-1975 (Box-folder 7: 12)
    See also Hedda Herwig
  - Barth, Hans (4), 1954-1962 (Box-folder 7: 13)
  - Bartholomew, Paul C. (4), 1963-1967 (Box-folder 7: 14)
  - Baruzzi, Arno (30), 1964-1984 (Box-folder 7: 15)
  - Basil Blackwell Publisher (Tony Sweeney) (3), 1983 (Box-folder 7: 16)
  - Baumgarten, Eduard (37), 1931-1960 (Box-folder 7: 17)
  - Bayerisches Staatsministerium für Arbeit und Soziale Fürsorge (2), 1962 (Box-folder 7: 18)
  - Bayerisches Staatsministerium für Unterricht und Kultus (Johannes von Elmenau, Otto Voll, Walter Krafft, Karl G. Hasemann, Theodor Maunz, Ludwig Huber) (99), 1959-1972 (Box-folder 7: 19)
    Includes correspondence regarding Geoffrey Barraclough
  - Beaumont, William H. (5), 1969 (Box-folder 7: 20)
  - Beck, Carl (5), 1959 (Box-folder 7: 21)
  - Beck, H. (3), 1965 (Box-folder 7: 22)
  - Beck, Hans-Georg (1), 1966 (Box-folder 7: 23)
  - Becker, C. (2), 1960 (Box-folder 7: 24)
  - Beckerath, Herbert von (6), 1939-1957 (Box-folder 7: 25)
  - Beg, A. S. (4), 1975 (Box-folder 7: 26)
  - Beierwaltes, Werner (1), 1983 (Box-folder 7: 27)
  - Bell, Roderick (5), 1975-1980 (Box-folder 7: 28)
  - Benesch, Otto (3), 1940-1945 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Bennett, Walter H. (University of Alabama) (4), 1943-1944 (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - Bennington College (Robert D. Leigh) (15), 1939 (Box-folder 8: 3)
  - Benz, Ernst (2), 1961 (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - Berger, H. (1), 1939 (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - Bergsträsser, Arnold (18), 1960-1962 (Box-folder 8: 6)
    See also Deutsche UNESCO-Kommission
  - Berheide, Michael (3), 1981 (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - Berliner Ferienakademie (Bernhard Hanssler, Hans Tietmeyer) (13), 1959 (Box-folder 8: 8)
  - Bermann-Fischer Verlag (22), 1938-1986 (Box-folder 8: 9)
    Includes contract and correspondence with Lissy Voegelin and Thomas Hollweck
  - Berns, Walter (4), 1959 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - Berstel, Hans and Hedwig (23), 1934-1958 (Box-folder 8: 11)
  - Bertier de Sauvigny, George de (26), 1964-1969 (Box-folder 8: 12)
  - Besson, Waldemar (6), 1960-1967 (Box-folder 8: 13)
  - Beum, Robert (8), 1972-1973 (Box-folder 8: 14)
  - Beyme, Klaus von (3), 1968 (Box-folder 8: 15)
  - Bickel, Alexander M. (1), 1961 (Box-folder 8: 16)
  - Bielcken, Harald (5), 1971-1978 (Box-folder 8: 17)
  - Bishirjian, Richard J. (37), 1969-1981 (Box-folder 8: 18)
  - Blackwell Publisher. See Basil Blackwell Publisher
  - Blake, R. P. (1), 1942 (Box-folder 8: 19)
  - Boatner, Mary Lynn (2), 1944 (Box-folder 8: 20)
  - Bogardus, George F. (3), 1981 (Box-folder 8: 21)
  - Bollingen Series, (3), 1954-1955 (Box-folder 8: 22)
  - Bolte, Karl Martin (4), 1965-1971 (Box-folder 8: 23)
  - Bom, Philip C. (3), 1963 (Box-folder 8: 24)
  - Bonnet, Henri (Institut International de Coopération Intellectuelle) (6), 1938 (Box-folder 8: 25)
  - Bonny Duala-M'bedy, L. J. (12), 1973-1980 (Box-folder 8: 26)
  - Bonvillain, Richard H. (5), 1966-1969 (Box-folder 8: 27)
  - Borty(?), Walter (1), undated (Box-folder 8: 28)
  - Bosl, Karl (3), 1966-1967 (Box-folder 8: 29)
  - Boston University (3), 1981-1983 (Box-folder 8: 30)
  - Bourassa, Guy (2), 1967 (Box-folder 8: 31)
  - Bourke, Vernon J. (2), 1956 (Box-folder 8: 32)
  - Bracher, K. D. (2), 1962-1967 (Box-folder 8: 33)
  - Bradford, Mel (6), 1970-1978 (Box-folder 8: 34)
  - Bradley, Phillips (5), 1939-1940 (Box-folder 8: 35)
  - Brandon, S. G. F. (3), 1966-1967 (Box-folder 8: 36)
  - Braun, Hanns (2), 1960 (Box-folder 8: 37)
  - Braunfels, Wolfgang (9), 1959-1971 (Box-folder 8: 38)
  - Brecht, Arnold (7), 1953-1962 (Box-folder 8: 39)
  - Breda, Herman Leo van (1), 1966 (Box-folder 8: 40)
  - Brinkmann, Donald (2), 1959 (Box-folder 8: 41)
  - Broch, Hermann (23), 1939-1949 (Box-folder 8: 42)
  - Brockhausen, Carl (7), 1938-1940 (Box-folder 8: 43)
  - Broersen, Theo (9), 1972-1980 (Box-folder 8: 44)
  - Brohi, A. K. (1), 1983 (Box-folder 8: 45)
  - Brooks, Cleanth and Tinkum (39), 1948-1980 (Box-folder 8: 46)
  - Browne, Martha Steffy (5), 1939-1981 (Box-folder 8: 47)
  - Browning, Robert W. (2), 1968 (Box-folder 8: 48)
  - Bruce, F. F. (1), 1966 (Box-folder 8: 49)
  - Brüning, Heinrich (24), 1938-1956 (Box-folder 8: 50)
  - Brunner, Otto (10), 1938-1962 (Box-folder 8: 51)
  - Bueno, Anibal Andres (4), 1979-1983 (Box-folder 8: 52)
  - Bueno C., Adolfo (7), 1967-1974 (Box-folder 8: 53)
  - Bühler, Ottmar, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 8: 54)
  - Bultmann, Rudolf (12), 1957-1971 (Box-folder 8: 55)
  - Bussanich, John (18), 1972-1981 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Bussmann, Karl F. (2), 1967 (Box-folder 9: 2)
  - Butterfield, H. (2), 1967 (Box-folder 9: 3)
  - Büttner, Friedemann (16), 1964-1971 (Box-folder 9: 4)
    Includes correspondence with Albert Hourani
  - Byrnes, V. Malcolm (4), 1966-1967 (Box-folder 9: 5)
  - C.H.Beck'sche Verlagsbuchhandlung (56), 1961-1977 (Box-folder 9: 6)
  - Calvo Serer, Rafael (2), 1959-1962 (Box-folder 9: 7)
  - Caringella, Paul (6), 1970-1971 (Box-folder 9: 8)
  - Carmichael, Peter (Louisiana State University) (4), 1942-1957 (Box-folder 9: 9)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace (6), 1938-1942 (Box-folder 9: 10)
  - Carter, Albert H. (2), 1966-1969 (Box-folder 9: 11)
  - Center for Coordination of Ancient and Modern Studies (Gerald F. Else) (25), 1969-1973 (Box-folder 9: 12)
  - Center for Cultural and Technical Interchange between East and West (9), 1967 (Box-folder 9: 13)
  - Center Journal (Kerry J. Koller) (1), 1983 (Box-folder 9: 14)
  - Cherniss, Harold (1), 1949 (Box-folder 9: 15)
  - Chroust, Anton-Hermann (1), 1963 (Box-folder 9: 16)
  - Claremont Institute. See American Political Science Association
  - Clark, Henry (Center for the Humanities, University of Southern California) (4), 1975-1977 (Box-folder 9: 17)
    Contains a long letter by Eric Voegelin on behaviorism. See also Speaking Engagements and Trips File, University of Southern California (Box 128, Folder 17).
  - Clebsch, William A. (2), 1975-1978 (Box-folder 9: 18)
  - Cohn, Norman (20), 1953-1973 (Box-folder 9: 19)
  - Coing, Helmut (2), 1960 (Box-folder 9: 20)
    See also Fritz Thyssen Stiftung.
  - Coker, Francis W. (1), 1949 (Box-folder 9: 21)
  - Colberg, Eckard (1), 1970 (Box-folder 9: 22)
  - Cole, R. Taylor (Duke University) (12), 1940-1963 (Box-folder 9: 23)
  - Cole, William J. (2), 1966 (Box-folder 9: 24)
  - Collier, David S. (1), 1966 (Box-folder 9: 25)
  - Columbia University (Arthur W. Macmahon, Irwin Edman) (7), 1938-1939 (Box-folder 9: 26)
  - Commons, John R. (University of Wisconsin) (2), 1938 (Box-folder 9: 27)
  - Cook, Peter K. See Peter Koch
  - Cook, Thomas I. (5), 1949-1954 (Box-folder 9: 28)
  - Cooper, F. B. K. (8), 1975-1980 (Box-folder 9: 29)
  - Cooper, Weldon (1), 1942 (Box-folder 9: 30)
  - Copeland, Lewis C. (2), 1942 (Box-folder 9: 31)
  - Corino, Karl (2), 1980 (Box-folder 9: 32)
  - Corrington, John William (4), 1974-1975 (Box-folder 9: 33)
    See also Richard J. Bishirjian, Stephen McKnight
  - Cotta, Sergio (1), 1976 (Box-folder 9: 34)
  - Coudenhove-Kalergi, Richard (1), 1941 (Box-folder 9: 35)
  - Cour, Raymond F. (4), 1969 (Box-folder 9: 36)
  - Crooks, Robert (8), 1970-1972 (Box-folder 9: 37)
  - Cruz-Bobzien, Nadinne (1), 1980 (Box-folder 9: 38)
  - Cullmann, Oscar (2), 1971 (Box-folder 9: 39)
  - Curtis Brown Ltd. (3), 1968 (Box-folder 9: 40)
  - Czernin, Edmund (2), 1942 (Box-folder 9: 41)
  - Czwientzek, Eva and Günter (37), 1969-1981 (Box-folder 9: 42)
    See also Carl J. Friedrich
  - Dallmayr, Fred R. (3), 1975-1976 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - Degrafell(?) (2), 1938-1940 (Box-folder 10: 2)
  - Deku, Henry (19), 1961-1965 (Box-folder 10: 3)
  - Dempf, Alois (37), 1949-1972 (Box-folder 10: 4)
  - Denver Quarterly (Gerald Chapman, Burton Feldman) (9), 1975-1976 (Box-folder 10: 5)